<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

<title>Constraint Lab</title>
<link href="/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
<link href="http://localhost:4000/"/>
<updated>2023-08-11T16:36:49-05:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000</id>
<author>
<name></name>
<email></email>
</author>


    

    

    
    <entry>
        <title>Biz Idea &amp;#35;1 - Liquor Store Distribution</title>
        <link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/biz-idea-1-liquor-store-distribution.html"/>
        <updated>2023-08-14T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
        <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/biz-idea-1-liquor-store-distribution</id>
        <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;context&quot;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry:&lt;/strong&gt; Liquor Store&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Problem:&lt;/strong&gt; Liquor stores sell commodities. A bottle of Wild Turkey is the same no matter where you buy it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constraint:&lt;/strong&gt; The market&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; Be more efficient, get more volume&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;idea&quot;&gt;Idea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Treat this as a delivery logisitics problem rather than a store. Rather than have a single store, open multiple stores:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stores should be delivery only.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stores are satellite warehouses that only store a popular subset of products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;A main warehouse stores the entire set of products.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The main warehouse is within one day drive of each satellite. Deliveries to each satellite occur every day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retail delivery is handled by the satellites. Promise same day delivery for the popular subset and next day delivery for everything else.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;advantages&quot;&gt;Advantages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Getting new liquor licenses for each new store is difficult and illegal in some locations. Opening and staffing a new store is difficult and expensive. In this case, a single license covers all sales (I assume).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More volume by covering more territory. Competing on price is easier when focusing on volume.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Inventory management could be easier as a single warehouse covers everything. You no longer need enough inventory for visual display.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Forced to win at efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Liquor stores often get access to limited products based on product sales. More volume via a larger market could result in better access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;difficulties&quot;&gt;Difficulties&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Marketing is different than being the “local liquor store”.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Managing employees is different.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delivery logistics and warehouse management is not trivial.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Legal issues abound with liquor. This whole idea is probably illegal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;scale-opportunities&quot;&gt;Scale Opportunities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are opportunities to leverage the ability to manage delivery logistics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expansion across the state is realistic (again, pending legalities).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expansion across statelines is realistic (again, pending legalities).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;There are lots of legal issues. Owning the stores that ship between each other could be a workaround.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Expansion into other delivery categories is realistic, e.g. household items.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;competition&quot;&gt;Competition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If Amazon sold liquor in the US as it does in other countries, it’s unlikely you could compete.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The convenience/impulse buy opportunity of driving by a liquor store is strong and unavailable.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Other liquor stores could band together to fight you legally.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I think liquor stores get weekly delivery, so inventory advantage probably grows only as you open more satellites.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
    </entry>
    


</feed>